[
    {
        "name": "First Amendment",
        "id": "first",
        "theme": "green",
        "quizzes": [
            {
                "type": "multi-select",
                "question": "Which freedoms are given by the Fist Amendment?",
                "options": [
                    "Freedom of Movement",
                    "Freedom of Religion",
                    "Right to a Fair Trial",
                    "Freedom of Speech",
                    "Freedom of Expression",
                    "Freedom to Murder",
                    "Freedom of Assembly",
                    "Right to Petition"
                ],
                "answer": [1,3,4,6,7]
            },
            {
                "type": "true-false",
                "question": "Telling lies about someone is protected by the First Amendment.",
                "answer": false
            },
            {
                "type": "true-false",
                "question": "Your parents can force you to practice a certain religion.",
                "answer": false
            },
            {
                "type": "four-quarter",
                "question": "What is not protected by the First Amendment?",
                "options": [
                    "Burning an American flag that belongs to you",
                    "Wearing a shirt with a slogan that may offend some people",
                    "Saying something mean about your Social Studies teacher",
                    "Protesting a law in a peaceful march"
                ],
                "answer": [2]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "name": "Second and Third Amendments",
        "id": "secondThird",
        "theme": "yellow",
        "quizzes": [
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": "Finish the first sentence of the Second Amendment",
				"start": "A well regulated",
				"end": ", being necessary to the security of a free State, the right of the people to keep and bear Arms, shall not be infringed.",
                "answer": "Militia"
            },
            {
                "type": "true-false",
                "question": "State and local governments have the right to limit the Second Amendment",
                "answer": true
            },
            {
                "type": "true-false",
                "question": "The government has the right to place soldiers in your home during a war",
                "answer": false
            },
            {
                "type": "picker",
                "question": "In how many court cases has the Third Amendment been the primary basis?",
                "min": 0,
				"max": 10,
                "answer": 0
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "name": "Fourth and Fifth Amendments",
        "id": "fourthFifth",
        "theme": "blue",
        "quizzes": [
            {
                "type": "true-false",
                "question": "Police always need a search warrant to search your belongings",
                "answer": false
            },
            {
                "type": "four-quarter",
                "question": "What type of search is not protected by the Fourth Amendment?",
                "options": [
                    "School silently installing spyware on your phone when you connect to their Wi-Fi network",
                    "School searching your backpack when it is in your locker",
                    "Police entering your home simply because you have a car that would make a good addition to the police's fleet",
                    "Police officer telling you to take off your shirt to see a really cool tatoo that you have"
                ],
                "answer": [0]
            },
            {
                "type": "true-false",
                "question": "The city can destroy your house without prior notice and compensation if they want to build a road there",
                "answer": false
            },
            {
                "type": "true-false",
                "question": "You can be forced to unlock your phone for a trial if you are using a face or fingerprint unlock.",
                "answer": true
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "name": "Sixth and Seventh Amendments",
        "id": "sixthSeventh",
        "theme": "red",
        "quizzes": [
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": "Finish the sentence:",
                "start": "In all criminal prosecutions, the accused shall enjoy the right to a speedy and",
				"end": ".",
                "answer": "public trial"
            },
            {
                "type": "true-false",
                "question": "The government has to provide you with a lawyer",
				"answer": true
            },
            {
                "type": "picker",
                "question": "You have the right to a jury if the value in controversy is more than (dollars)",
				"min": 0,
				"max": 100,
				"step": 5,
                "answer": 20
            },
            {
                "type": "picker",
                "question": "What is the minimum amount of members in a jury",
                "min": 1,
                "max": 12,
                "answer": 6
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "name": "Eighth Amendment",
        "id": "eighth",
        "theme": "green",
        "quizzes": [
            {
                "type": "fill-two-blanks",
                "question": "What are the protections of the Eighth Amendment?",
                "answer": [
					"excessive bail",
					"cruel and unusual punishment"
				]
            },
            {
                "type": "true-false",
                "question": "Does capital punishment (death penalty) count as cruel and unusual punishment as long as it is standardized?",
                "answer": false
            },
            {
                "type": "four-quarter",
                "question": "What is the only cat in the world that can’t retract its claws?",
                "options": [
                    "Meerkat",
                    "Bobcat",
                    "Cheetah",
                    "Siamese"
                ],
                "answer": [2]
            },
            {
                "type": "toggle-translate",
                "question": "Which chemical symbols are incorrect?",
                "options": [
                    [
                        "Helium",
                        "He"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Tungsten",
                        "W"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Lithium",
                        "Lt"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Nickel",
                        "Ni"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Copper",
                        "C"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Zinc",
                        "Zn"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Cadmium",
                        "Cd"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Potassium",
                        "K"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Silicon",
                        "Sn"
                    ]
                ],
                "answer": [2,4,8]
            },
            {
                "type": "true-false",
                "question": "The vitreous humour is found in the human eye.",
                "answer": true
            },
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": "What’s the third color of the rainbow?",
                "answer": "Yellow"
            },
            {
                "type": "picker",
                "question": "How many toes do most birds have?",
                "min": 2,
                "max": 12,
                "answer": 8
            },
            {
                "type": "picker",
                "question": "If the temperature in Centigrade is minus 40 degrees what is the temperature in Fahrenheit?",
                "min": -100,
                "max": 0,
                "step": 5,
                "answer": -40
            },
            {
                "type": "four-quarter",
                "question": "What sort of creature is a fluke?",
                "options": [
                    "Bird",
                    "Insect",
                    "Worm",
                    "Bear"
                ],
                "answer": [2]
            },
            {
                "type": "fill-two-blanks",
                "question": "What two metals together make brass?",
                "answer": [
                    "Copper",
                    "Zinc"
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "name": "TV & Movies",
        "id": "tvmovies",
        "theme": "purple",
        "quizzes": [
            {
                "type": "multi-select",
                "question": "Select the actors who played James Bond:",
                "options": [
                    "Sean Connery",
                    "Clive Owen",
                    "Timothy Dalton",
                    "David Niven",
                    "Clint Eastwood",
                    "Toby Stephens"
                ],
                "answer": [0,2,3,5]
            },
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": "In which movie were Kevin Bacon, Bill Paxton, and Tom hanks on an aircraft?",
                "answer": "Apollo 13"
            },
            {
                "type": "four-quarter",
                "question": "In which famous sci-fi film did Robert Patrick play an assassin?",
                "options": [
                    "Blade Runner",
                    "Terminator 2",
                    "Watchmen",
                    "Forbidden Planet"
                ],
                "answer": [1]
            },
            {
                "type": "single-select",
                "question": "What was the name of Mork and Mindy’s child?",
                "options": [
                    "Micah",
                    "Morty",
                    "Mearth",
                    "Magnus"
                ],
                "answer": [2]
            },
            {
                "type": "picker",
                "question": "How old is Bart Simpson?",
                "min": 6,
                "max": 13,
                "answer": 10
            },
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": "Where had King Kong lived before coming to New York in the 1933 film \"King Kong\"?",
                "end": "island",
                "answer": "skull"
            },
            {
                "type": "true-false",
                "question": "Stanley Kubrick directed the 1971 film \"THX 1138.\"",
                "answer": false
            },
            {
                "type": "picker",
                "question": "The film \"Ben Hur\" holds the record for winning more Oscars than any other movie. How many?",
                "min": 4,
                "max": 15,
                "answer": 11
            },
            {
                "type": "four-quarter",
                "question": "Which Spielberg film gives an unflattering account of Carcharodon Carcharias?",
                "options": [
                    "Saving Private Ryan",
                    "E.T.",
                    "Jaws",
                    "The Color Purple"
                ],
                "answer": [2]
            },
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": "In which film did Robert De Niro ask “Are you talkin’ to me?”",
                "answer": "Taxi Driver"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "name": "Music",
        "id": "music",
        "theme": "blue",
        "quizzes": [
            {
                "type": "four-quarter",
                "question": "Who was the youngest Beatle?",
                "options": [
                    "John",
                    "Paul",
                    "George",
                    "Ringo"
                ],
                "answer": [2]
            },
            {
                "type": "multi-select",
                "question": "Best known for playing the trumpet:",
                "options": [
                    "Miles Davis",
                    "Chet Baker",
                    "Art Farmer",
                    "John Coltrane",
                    "Dizzy Gillespie",
                    "Freddie Hubbard"
                ],
                "answer": [0,1,2,4,5]
            },
            {
                "type": "toggle-translate",
                "question": "Which nationality of the following composers is incorrect?",
                "options": [
                    [
                        "Johann Sebastian Bach",
                        "German"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Sergei Rachmaninov",
                        "Czechoslovakian"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Frederic Chopin",
                        "Polish"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Giacoma Puccini",
                        "Italian"
                    ],
                    [
                        "George Gershwin",
                        "Austrian"
                    ]
                ],
                "answer": [1,4]
            },
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": "Prior to forming BAD which group did Mick Jones Belong to?",
                "answer": "The Clash"
            },
            {
                "type": "single-select-item",
                "question": "Frank Sinatra covered this song made famous by a popular Jim Henson character.",
                "options": [
                    "Welcome to Sesame Street",
                    "It’s not Easy Bein’ Green",
                    "Hugga Wugga",
                    "Wild Thing"
                ],
                "answer": [1]
            },
            {
                "type": "true-false",
                "question": "Queen’s Bohemian Rhapsody was a Christmas number one hit in the UK, twice.",
                "answer": true
            },
            {
                "type": "picker",
                "question": "How many symphonies did Beethoven write?",
                "min": 1,
                "max": 16,
                "answer": 9
            },
            {
                "type": "single-select",
                "question": "Which was the first Beach Boys number one song in the US?",
                "options": [
                    "Kokomo",
                    "Help Me",
                    "Rhonda",
                    "I Get Around",
                    "Good Vibrations"
                ],
                "answer": [3]
            },
            {
                "type": "four-quarter",
                "question": "Noah Benjamin Lenox is an experimental musician better known as which animal?",
                "options": [
                    "Grizzly Bear",
                    "Panda Bear",
                    "Gorrilla",
                    "Pitbull"
                ],
                "answer": [1]
            },
            {
                "type": "single-select-item",
                "question": "After Simeon Oliver Coxe III incorporated a 1940s audio oscillator his band was renamed this, after a William Butler Yeats poem:",
                "options": [
                    "Silver Apples",
                    "Golden Oranges",
                    "White Rose",
                    "Black Moth"
                ],
                "answer": [0]
            }
        ]
    },    {
        "name": "Entertainment",
        "id": "entertainment",
        "theme": "red",
        "quizzes": [
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": "Where was superman born?",
                "answer": "Krypton"
            },
            {
                "type": "four-quarter",
                "question": "What catchphrase is associated with the Daleks from Doctor Who?",
                "options": [
                    "Eradicate",
                    "Exterminate",
                    "Eliminate",
                    "Execute"
                ],
                "answer": [1]
            },
            {
                "type": "picker",
                "question": "In the film Cool Hand Luke, how many hard boiled eggs did Paul Newman eat to win a bet?",
                "min": 20,
                "max": 80,
                "answer": 50
            },
            {
                "type": "true-false",
                "question": "Frank Sinatra paid a $240,000 ransom to free his kidnapped son.",
                "answer": true
            },
            {
                "type": "multi-select",
                "question": "Which two British actors have played Obi Wan Kenobi in the Star Wars films?",
                "options": [
                    "Sir Alec Guinness",
                    "David Prowse",
                    "James Earl Jones",
                    "Harrison Ford",
                    "Ewan McGregor",
                    "Anthony Daniels"
                ],
                "answer": [0,4]
            },
            {
                "type": "picker",
                "question": "How many Oscars were won by the film Matrix at the 2000 Academy Awards ceremony?",
                "min": 0,
                "max": 11,
                "answer": 4
            },
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": "Late American artist Andy Warhol observed:",
                "start": "“Two people kissing always looks like ",
                "end": ".”",
                "answer": "Fish"
            },
            {
                "type": "single-select",
                "question": "Who played Dr. John Hammond in Jurassic Park?",
                "options": [
                    "Anthony Hopkins",
                    "Jeff Goldblum",
                    "Richard Attenborough",
                    "Emmet Brown"
                ],
                "answer": [2]
            },
            {
                "type": "picker",
                "question": "What year did the Live Aid concerts take place?",
                "min": 1965,
                "max": 1990,
                "answer": 1985
            },
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": "What is Mr. Burns’ first name?",
                "answer": "Charles"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "name": "Sports",
        "id": "sports",
        "theme": "purple",
        "quizzes": [
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": "What is the national sport of Canada?",
                "answer": "Lacrosse"
            },
            {
                "type": "four-quarter",
                "question": "Which country won every Olympic Men’s hockey gold medal from 1928 to 1956?",
                "options": [
                    "Canada",
                    "Russia",
                    "India",
                    "USA"
                ],
                "answer": [2]
            },
            {
                "type": "true-false",
                "question": "A biathlon event consists of running a half marathon and biking 56 miles.",
                "answer": false
            },
            {
                "type": "picker",
                "question": "How many players are in a game of water polo?",
                "min": 10,
                "max": 25,
                "answer": 14
            },
            {
                "type": "toggle-translate",
                "question": "Which sports and team names are incorrectly associated?",
                "options": [
                    [
                        "Cleveland Indians",
                        "Baseball"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Leicester Tigers",
                        "Rugby Union"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Bradford Bulls",
                        "Hockey"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Belle Vue Aces",
                        "Poker"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Wigan Wasps",
                        "Lacrosse"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Kent Spitfires",
                        "Cricket"
                    ]
                ],
                "answer": [2,3,4]
            },
            {
                "type": "multi-select",
                "question": "Which cities have hosted the Olympic games?",
                "options": [
                    "Athens",
                    "Lake Placid",
                    "Innsbruck",
                    "New York",
                    "Capetown",
                    "St. Mortiz"
                ],
                "answer": [0,1,2,4,5]
            },
            {
                "type": "four-quarter",
                "question": "Which American was the best paid sportsman in 1920?",
                "options": [
                    "Jack Dempsey",
                    "Babe Ruth",
                    "Big Bill Tilden",
                    "Bobby Jones"
                ],
                "answer": [1]
            },
            {
                "type": "single-select-item",
                "question": " What do you call a stadium used for cycling events?",
                "options": [
                    "Cycleplex",
                    "Velodrome",
                    "Pumptrack",
                    "Speedway"
                ],
                "answer": [1]
            },
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": "In 1954, Joe Di Maggio married Norma Jean Baker who was also known as?",
                "answer": "Marilyn Monroe"
            },
            {
                "type": "picker",
                "question": "About how many kilometers are in a marathon?",
                "min": 10,
                "max": 65,
                "answer": 42
            }
        ]
    }
]
